Emily, something strange happened today.
>> Really? What happened?
>> I sent a text to my classmate. I wrote,
"I will send you a message later."
He texted back, "Oh, are you new here?"
I was so surprised.
How did he know I am new?
>> Oh, I think I understand.
That's kind of funny.
>> Wait, you understand it? Why did he
think I am new?
>> Because native speakers don't usually
say send a message. They usually say
text.
Really? But my textbook says send a
message is correct.
>> The textbook is right. It's not wrong.
But in real life, in everyday talk,
people just say text.
>> So if I want to sound more natural, I
should say, I'll text you.
>> Exactly. I'll text you sounds like
normal natural English.
>> Ah,
now I see it.
>> Phone English has many small things like
this. A lot of learners study for years
and still don't know them.
>> Then
I really need to learn more phone
English.
>> Don't worry. Today you can learn with my
day. I'll tell you about my day
yesterday with my phone.
>> Your day with your phone?
>> Yes. From morning to night. I'll show
you how I use it.
Every little thing, every little word.
You can learn English through stories
like this.
>> Okay, let's go. I'm ready. Slow English
practice time.
Every morning I use my phone as my alarm
clock. Beep beep. It wakes me up.
>> You use your phone as an alarm clock?
>> Yes. Many people do that now.
The alarm rings and I press snooze.
>> Snooze.
Snooze means I sleep a few more minutes.
Maybe five minutes, maybe 10.
>> Oh, so snooze means sleep a little more.
Just a short time.
>> Exactly.
I press snooze, then I wake up again.
>> If I press snooze, I will sleep for two
more hours.
That's dangerous.
After the alarm, I look at my phone and
check my notifications.
>> Notifications?
>> Yes. Notifications are the little
messages on the screen.
They tell me new things like new emails,
new texts, news and so on.
>> Ah, so notification means hey something
new for you. I can say I have 10
notifications this morning.
>> Perfect. That's a great sentence.
So, in the morning, your phone is your
alarm, your snooze button, and your
notifications,
right? My day starts with my phone.
After my alarm, I go to the kitchen. I
make breakfast. And of course, I take my
phone with me.
Do you really need your phone for
breakfast?
>> Yes. While I eat, I look at my phone.
>> I open the news app.
>> The news.
>> Not a P. We just say app.
>> Oh, app.
>> Yes. like map app, music app, weather
app. Just say app.
>> App.
>> Good. Say it one more time.
>> App. App.
>> Perfect. So, I open the news app and
read the headlines.
>> Headlines.
What are headlines?
>> Headlines are the big news titles you
see first. For example, big storm today
or new movie is number one.
>> Ah, so a headline is a short news title.
>> Exactly.
>> And after that I check my group chat.
>> Your friends text you in the morning.
>> Uh, no, they text at night, but I read
everything in the morning.
>> That's a lot to read.
So, you open the news app, read the
headlines, and then check your group
chat.
>> Yes, that is my breakfast with my phone.
And remember, app not a easy English
snack.
>> Look, Emily, I just got a text with only
emojis. Just a smiley face and a slice
of pizza.
>> That's easy. It means let's eat pizza
and be happy.
>> True. Emojis are like a new language.
>> Yeah.
Sometimes I think I speak emoji better
than English.
After breakfast, I leave home. I put on
my headphones.
>> Headphones? Let me guess. for music,
right?
>> Yes. I open my music app. I love my
music app in the morning.
>> Music app. I have one, too, but I often
forget to open it. I just sit on the bus
in silence.
>> You need music in the morning.
Sometimes I listen to songs. Sometimes I
listen to an audio book.
>> Audio book. You mean like a book that
talks to you?
>> Exactly. A book you can listen to.
>> I listen to audiobooks when I'm on the
bus or on the train.
>> That's cool.
My books just sit on the shelf. I never
read them.
Oh, look. I see two missed calls.
>> Missed calls? So, your phone rang and
you didn't answer.
>> Yes. Missed calls are calls you don't
answer. If I don't want pickup, I get a
missed call.
>> Got it.
So if I'm sleeping and my mom calls,
later I see five missed calls.
>> Exactly. And later I call back.
>> Call back after missed calls. That one
is easy.
>> Right.
So, on the way to school, I use my
headphones, my music app or audio book,
and I also check my missed calls.
When I'm in class, I don't use my phone.
I put it away. My bag is closed. Phone
inside.
>> Put it away. So, you hide it in your
bag.
>> Yes, I put it away. and don't look at
it. I also turn on do not disturb.
>> Do not disturb. That means no calls, no
texts, right?
>> Yes.
When I turn on do not disturb, I don't
get calls. I don't get texts. I don't
hear sounds.
Oh, so do not disturb makes the phone
quiet.
Very quiet.
>> Exactly. Do not disturb equals total
silence.
And I stop the vibration, too.
>> Vibration?
You mean when the phone shakes?
>> Yes. the little buzz. Vibration is the
shake.
>> So, no ring, no vibration. The phone is
completely quiet,
>> right? No sound, no vibration.
So, in class, I put my phone away, I
turn on do not disturb, and I stop
vibration.
The teacher is happy. At lunchtime, I go
to the cafeteria. To get in, I scan the
QR code on my phone. Beep. Door open.
>> QR code. What is that?
>> A QR code is the little black and white
square you scan.
Oh, QR code. I see.
>> Then I walk into the cafeteria.
>> Cafeteria. Oh, you mean the big room at
school where students eat?
>> Yes, exactly. The cafeteria is the place
where many students eat.
Then I open the cafeteria app and order
my lunch. No waiting in a long line.
>> So you order on the app and later you
just pick it up.
>> Yes. My phone tells me when my food is
ready.
Sometimes my friends come too. We sit,
talk, and wait for our names on the
screen.
So, your phone does everything.
Door, order, pickup.
>> And before we eat, we take a selfie.
>> Oh, I always said take a picture of
myself.
>> That is okay. But we usually just say
selfie.
>> Selfie. Short and easy.
>> Exactly. We always take a selfie before
we start to eat.
>> First selfie, then food. That's the
rule.
>> English snack.
John, have you ever heard of a pocket
call?
>> A pocket call? Like call your pocket?
>> No.
A pocket call is when your phone calls
someone by mistake from your pocket or
your bag.
>> Ah, I know that.
I once pocket called my teacher.
It was so embarrassing.
>> After lunch, I walk to the library.
My phone comes with me because I use it
there, too.
>> Really?
You need your phone even in the library?
>> Yes. If I want to borrow a book, I open
the library app and scan the QR code.
>> Scan, like take a picture.
>> Almost.
A scan is like a photo but for a code.
The phone reads the code and gets the
information.
Ah, scan the code. I understand.
>> Yes. Now I can borrow the book. Then I
sit down at a table. Time to study. Shh.
This is the library.
>> Okay, I will be quiet.
>> Wait,
why are you looking at your phone again?
I'm using flashcards.
Flash cards are small cards with a word
or picture on them. They help me
remember words.
>> Ah, flash cards on your phone.
>> Yes, a flashc card app. It is very
simple.
>> Cool. And what is that on the video?
>> Those are subtitles.
Subtitles are the words at the bottom of
the video. They help me read while I
listen.
Oh, I see words at the bottom.
Subtitles. Nice.
And my phone is on do not disturb again.
After the library, I walk home.
I open my phone and check the weather
app.
>> Weather app? You mean it tells you if it
will rain or be sunny?
>> Yes.
It shows sun, rain, clouds, snow. Today
it says sunny.
>> So no umbrella.
Huh?
Good news,
>> right? The weather app saves me. If it
says rain, I take my umbrella. If it
says sun, I don't need it.
>> Weather app. Umbrella. Sunny.
I can say, "My weather app says rainy,
so I take an umbrella."
>> Perfect sentence. Sometimes if I want to
visit a friend, I open the map app with
GPS. It shows me the way step by step.
>> Oh, the map app with GPS. So I can say,
I use GPS to go to my friend's house.
>> Exactly. Weather app and map app with
GPS. Two apps that make life easier.
English snack again. Do you know the
phrase call it a day, John?
Is it about making a phone call?
>> No. Call it a day means stop working.
Finish for today.
>> Oh, so no more study. We call it a day.
That's easy.
At home, I sit on the sofa. I open a
video app and I stream a show.
>> Stream? You mean watch online?
>> Yes, stream means watch online, not
download.
>> Ah, I also stream shows, but sometimes I
watch without subtitles.
Subtitles help a lot. They are the words
at the bottom of the screen.
>> Okay. Subtitles.
So I can say I stream a movie with
subtitles.
>> Exactly. That is a very natural
sentence.
>> Subtitles stream. Now I understand.
In the evening, I make a few calls. I
call my mom and I call my friend.
>> Do you call with your phone?
>> Careful. We say call on my phone or use
my phone to call, not call with my
phone.
>> Oh, I always said call with my phone.
>> Many learners do, but it sounds strange
to native speakers. It's better to say I
call on my phone.
>> Okay. I call on my phone.
I call on my phone. I will practice
that.
>> Great. Now it sounds natural.
>> Sometimes when people don't answer, I
leave a voicemail.
>> Voicemail. That is a message with your
voice.
>> Exactly. Like a voice note. You speak
and the other person listens later.
>> Okay.
I can say, "Sorry, I missed your call. I
left a voicemail."
>> Perfect sentence. Before bed, I set my
alarm on my phone. Beep beep for
tomorrow morning.
>> Good idea. So, your phone will wake you
up again?
>> Then I put my phone on do not disturb,
brush my teeth, and get ready for sleep.
Do not disturb again. No calls, no
sounds. Perfect for night.
>> Exactly.
Then I close my eyes and sleep.
>> So your whole day is with your phone.
From the alarm in the morning to the
alarm at night.
>> That's right. My day with my phone. So,
John, think about one full day with my
phone. In the morning, alarm, snooze,
notifications,
then breakfast, news app, headlines,
group chat.
>> On the way to school, headphones, music
app, audio book, missed calls, and call
back
>> in class. Put it away. Do not disturb.
No vibration, total silence.
>> At lunch, cafeteria. Scan the QR code.
Cafeteria app. Order food. Selfie.
Pocket call
>> in the library. Scan to borrow.
Flashcards to study, subtitles to read,
and do not disturb to stay focused.
>> Walking home. Weather app. Sun or rain,
umbrella, and map app with GPS.
>> In the evening, stream a show, watch
with subtitles.
>> At night, make calls, leave a voicemail
if they don't answer, set the alarm, do
not disturb, then sleep.
>> My phone never rests. True. But every
time you use it, you also learn small
English words.
>> Exactly.
Many learners study for years and still
make these mistakes.
>> But not you now, John.
>> Right now I know. Next time I will text
you, not send you a message.
>> Yes, that's the idea. a day with my
phone and a lot of English
>> and a lot of slow English practice
>> and we learn English through stories
every day.